T: +225 0749141942 0506546058 E: <u>sendtoakaffou@yahoo.fr</u> t.akaffou@afdb.org

SUMMARY

Seasoned professional and IT lead with 10+ years of experience in establishing and managing information systems, digital platforms and databases, with a well-established track record of delivered and over-achieved KPI's at operations strategy implementation level. Key member of crosscutting teams playing a central role in setting up strategic relationships within the African Development Bank (Bank). Management support in providing training, coordination, and decision-making tools for successful commitments implementation gained from the Bank as well as Government Officials of Côte d'Ivoire.

Antoine was coordinating and monitoring large projects portfolios for operational units as data and portfolio analyst, including improving and enhancing the portfolio performance, data quality at entry and quarterly reports. Background and proven experience in operations and financial management, as well as budget monitoring. Familiar with grant and funding management procedures, involving bilateral and multi-donors trust funds, and co-financing. Knowledge of Bank's funding concepts, principles, methods and techniques of work program administration, within project supervision and monitoring.

Very ambitious, results-oriented, and paying attention to details, with strong analytical and interpersonal skills. Exceptional at working independently and being a great team player. I have the ability to work very well, in both French and English. Strong organizational skills and capacity to handle multiple tasks under tight deadlines with a high level of attention to detail, including comprehensive reports and MS Excel skills, working on a daily basis to successfully implement projects.

EDUCATION

Executive Master of Science (MSc) in Finance

Master's degree in Project Management

Master's degree in Computer Science

■ Bachelor's degree in Computer Science

EM Lyon Business School, France (2020)

Institut des Technologies d'Abidjan - EFREI, Paris (2015)

Institut des Technologies d'Abidjan - EFREI, Paris (2010)

Institut des Technologies d'Abidjan - EFREI, Paris (2007)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

The African Development Bank Group (Education and Skills Development Division (AHHD1))

Senior Operations Assistant | Abidjan; July 2020 - now. Responsibilities and Key Achievements

- Leads a portfolio worth at US\$ 10 billion including active operations, lending and IO pipeline within dashboards and trends on a regular basis, reports and provides data in easily digestible ways and analytics, enabling more exploring data
- Provides functional support for business applications, by contributing in particular to the stability of the applications and the achievement of the service levels committed within the Bank, and this in compliance with internal rules and processes
- Represents Management, on weekly/monthly basis, at sectorial work program and budget reviews meetings, advises on
 priorities for budget resources reallocation and needs for the respective regions, prepares regular (mostly quarterly) reports
- Technically supported and leads a multisector operational portfolio within the Bank worth at over US\$ 400 million of projects spanning loans, grants, & multilateral trust funds resources, managing transactions processing and disbursements
- Key focal person within AHHD1 Division that coordinates, monitors, and reports on the work program, as well as the budget implementation and utilization, including Bank's administrative budget and multilateral trust funds management.
- Coordinates with projects team to establish priorities and proactively sets direction for engineering projects team, trains sector focal points in budget system and range of technologies to support portfolio, leads desk research informing strategy.
- Establishes an active portfolio system for the Rwanda Office (CORW) to support projects monitoring and reporting, conducts key analysis bringing to 18% from 27% the flagged-red operations rating, develops a monitoring dashboard on supervision missions' status within IPR/PCR setting, projects procurement overview, consultancy contracts improvement
- Supports effective grant management across various areas of responsibility: grant making, grant monitoring and reporting, capacity building, and stakeholder engagement initiatives, as well as in helping issue, monitor, and report to Bank's donors
- Carries out collection and data analysis of supervision's outcomes/outputs, disbursement ledgers and procurement increasing portfolio performance rate up to 68% in quarter 3 against less than 36% early with a target to unflag 4 projects.
- Co-author providing narrative/analysis on behalf of the Dept to the Review on Annual Development Effectiveness Report
- Works closely with the African Investment Forum (AIF) Team to solve challenges in the lead up to the market days in providing analytical, technical/admin support to 2022 preparation in real-time mapping of sponsors/investors/partners,
- Coordinates AIF digital platform's implementation and updates the boardrooms agenda, ensures data quality assurance and integrity get approved for the 2022 market days' success, reports on data management-monitoring to AIF Lead Team
- Actively manages the AIF master deal tracker database within cleaning and keeping records of AIF registration database,
- Works in enhancing the AIF Management Information System tool and data warehouse informing business development
- Analyzes portfolio risks and performance to inform new business strategy and key focusing on all red-flagged operations.

The African Development Bank Group (Non-sovereign Operations Support & Private Sector Department (PINS)) Operations Assistant & IT Engineer | Abidjan; April 2019-June 2020. Responsibilities and Key Achievements

- Enhanced the development and maintenance of the PINS Platform "Non-sovereign Operations Document Support Tool" (NSO DST) for improving proper records management, information storage and knowledge on lessons learned sharing
- Developed the revised version of funding-requests platform that I created in 2018 for funding management and processing
- Provided analytical support to portfolio/task managers in portfolio management and monitoring at HQ and regional levels

- Created an IT platform dealing with the portfolio management and monitoring with a key "spotlight" on quarterly trends
- Representing, on (bi)weekly and monthly basis, the Department in portfolio, work program and budget reviews meetings
- · Prepared quarterly and bi-annual budget reconciliation and work program execution including providing drafts and reports
- Worked with front office equity cluster, managing equity portfolio, providing key updates as well dashboard and reporting
- Established working relationships facilitating gathering of information, data/files for records as required by management.
- Established an IT dashboard for monitoring key figures for the preparation of monthly and quarterly work program reports for East, South, North, and Nigeria regions, including each activity progress, disbursement rates and data analysis reports.
- Supported Manager and Task Managers with various operational tasks within the corporate applications, in compliance with internal rules and procedures, including: (i) recruitment of staff and individual/firm's consultants; (ii) contracts processing in SAP-PS/FM; (ii) preparation of projects Implementation Progress (IPRs) and Completion (PCRs) reports.
- Consolidated the list of 67 boardrooms projects sponsors for blast based on 76 sheets of projects sponsors information
 and led data analysis in order to disseminate both the physical participants from virtual ones due to hybrid mode adopted
- Led AIF boardroom packs creation and project documentation for deal reviews, boardrooms, B2B sessions and data for the AIF deal gallery, ensuring optimization of the deal tracker database and generating some analytic reports on-demand.

The Ministry of Health and Public Hygiene of Côte d'Ivoire (National Coordination for ICT Integration) ICT National Coordinator (Assistant) | Abidjan; Sept. 2018-April 2019. Responsibilities and Key Achievements

- Created assets management database, designed dashboards and provided reporting to explore financing data from WHO, UNICEF, UNFPA and UNAIDS data files, and supported preparation of the Ministry's 2019-2022 annual work program
- Implemented annual strategic development axes by carrying data collection and led the e-health funds of USD 10+ billion
- Supervised 13 eHealth projects including data monitoring, ensuring good quality at entry reflected on the ministry website
- Provided operational/technical support with high degree of accuracy and a strong capacity to produce high-quality work
- · Contributed to the draft of the e-health national policy document ensuring the quality of the ministry portfolio performance
- Coordinated e-records updates on daily/weekly basis and managed backup integrity to avoid data damages and corruptions
- Prepared regular (mostly quarterly) reports that provide analytical insight to multiple dimensions of the ministry e-Health portfolio, including impact of new platform "Dossier Patient Informatisé" and profitability, and the implementation trend
- Participated in and take minutes of portfolio related meetings and the business development discussions with stakeholders
- Attended in project-related meetings, both virtually and in-person, drafted minutes as well as contributed to develop the
 ministry's annual work plan and performance monitoring indicators, and provided the follow-up dashboard for overview
- Conducted desk review and research for available health grants and oversaw the process for writing grant proposals that
 outline how better using money including reviewing budget completeness, and compliance, as team leader and focal point.

The African Development Bank Group (Private Sector Development Department (OPSD)) Team Assistant and IT Specialist | Abidjan; June 2015-Sept 2018. Responsibilities and Key Achievements

- Developed the wide e-OPSD Department's Platform including databases built from scratch, designed, architecture, and programmed from scratch, including providing reporting, automatic and on-demand, as well as staff training, as following:
 ✓ the e-Funding-requests application for clients funding management and processing, including breakdown per division
 ✓ the e-Budget management to follow up the budget utilization and monitoring, within needs assessment and reallocation
 ✓ the e-Customers relationship management application including both internal and external business cards management
 ✓ the e-Consultancy management monitoring consultants' recruitments in compliance with Bank policies, rules and procedures, as well as conducting the dissemination of the Bank's applicable Delegation of Authority Matrix
- Worked with equity cluster team at front office leading equity portfolio, providing key update and automatising reporting
- Reviewed the process and procedures related to the private sector's equity operations in collaboration with task managers
- Assisted in analyzing, understanding, acquainting with financial & economic models close to structuring/modelling team
- Represented, on a weekly and monthly basis, the OPSD Department in the Program and Budget Department (SNPB) work program and budget meetings, as well as on project disbursements status review from SAP-PS with budget coordinators.
- Assessed file records problems and created a proper record management for information storage and retrieval for our team
- Provided technical assistance to staff and task managers in the use of the Bank's IT systems such SAP-PS; BPPS, SRAS
- Provide support and back up Portfolio Officers in completion of compliance actions such as credit ratings completions and implementation progress reports, completion of equity-rated actions, record-keeping, and ensured archiving well done
- Drove regularly outstanding issues/updates (flagged operations, loans and grants for cancellation, overdue special accounts, and indicative operation pipeline) on weekly basis in close collaboration with Front Office Program Coordinator

The Ministry of Health and Fight against AIDS of Côte d'Ivoire (IT Management and Coordination Office) Information Management Officer (Assistant) | Abidjan; Dec 2011-June 2015.Responsibilities and Key Achievements

- Developed an application from scratch, leading to a better management of annual incentive bonuses within an accurate calculation and processing of staff payroll. I innovated by building, designing, programming and implementing the system
- Coordinated the Ministry's Website updates on a regular basis including a real communication approach with the 65 health departmental directions spanning on 27 regional hubs at country level and records on all e-Health operations status
- Enhanced capacity building for national campaign against malaria funded by Global Fund: 12 million mosquito nets, including team training and dissemination of supporting files during the fields work program supervision and discussion.
- Reviewed draft report of key institutional project 'Dossier Patient Informatisé' within quality at entry for 900+ data lines
- Conducted the work programme mission for the medico-economic report of telemedicine project and e-Health integration
- Coordinated the communication materials during the 2013 national campaign against malaria and also information storage

- Ensured and coordinated staff training enhancing field offices operations effectiveness as per the management's guidance and including a gain of saving of more than 40% of the budget allocated worth USD 100,000 from the consultancy services
- Provided operational and technical assistance to the Ministry's Front Office including assisting in annual budget preparation and work program and implementing a dashboard for monitoring payroll and budget management.

Cabinet Sciences and Metiers Consulting (IT Solutions and Customers Care Department) IT Junior Consultant | Abidjan; October 2009 to October 2011. Responsibilities and Key Achievements

- Key database administrator (DBA) ensuring the configuration and update of pharmacy management software are provided
- Results-focused and effective, developed an automated dashboard with key performance indicators for 36 pharmacies
- Acted as a trusted adviser to users, guiding them on platform and ensuring they derive highest value from own engagement
- Provided technical leadership and support to clients, knowledge and lesson sharing with internal and external stakeholders
- Carried-out compilation, prepared briefs and quarterly reports as required by management as well as providing trainings
- Assisted the management by providing inputs and comments on contracts, and other documents relating to marketing axis
- Conducted frequent monitoring of work programs and drafted reports, involving annual inventory for sales trend analysis
- Provided online needs visualization including translating business needs to technical specifications via PPT presentations.
- Configured and updated pharmacy management software, trained staff members, and reported to the Principal Consultant
- Managed and controlled IT resources state, conducted backup and archiving, provided drugs sales' data analysis and trend
- Monitored client's portfolio including 36 pharmacies, led database and archiving management, and coordinated IT issues
- Ensured good level of user competence, acted in supporting organization and staff capacity building, supervised reporting.

MTN Côte d'Ivoire S.A., HQ, Côte d'Ivoire (Business Intelligence Department)

Business Intelligence (BI) Engineer | Abidjan; June 2009 to September 2009. Responsibilities and Key Achievements

- Developed analytical and statistical tools, created/ managed databases, sometimes from scratch, as back-office engineer
- Performed the installation and configuration of DBs, Oracle 10i and 11g databases, MS SQL Server, MySQL, MS Access,
- Monitored data volume growth, ensured periodic backup and databases restoration, configured daily strategic SQL queries
- Monitored the consistency, integrity and availability of backups, ensure their availability, and managed various data sources that clears the status of client requests, also designed dashboard to improve incoming and outgoing calls reporting
- Ensure the management of physical (tablespace, file groups) and logical (partitioning) storage spaces, conducted analytics
- Set up IT solutions and databases, led data analysis, completed and deployed the newly "High value clients" software.

ANNEX

Professional Training Background and Certificates of Completion Acquired

❖ Budget Management and Work Program Planning

October 2022
October 2022
May 2022
May 2022
March 2022
March 2022
August 2021
December 2020
June 2020
. 2019-April 2020
January 2020
October 2018
April 2017

Training Centre of African Development Bank Group - One Bank Knowledge Exchange Network

September 2016